Salvador Luria Papers 1923-1992 Mss.Ms.Coll.39
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1938-1992; 15.5 linear feet
  - Puck, Theodore T., 1949, 1974 (Box 25)
    See also Ser.I, Lennox, Edwin S.
  - Pugliese, Luisa, 1985 (Box 25)
  - Puig, Juan, 1970 (Box 25)
  - Purcell, Edward, 1972 (Box 25)
  - Purdue University, 1981-1982 (Box 25)
  - Putnam, Frank W., 1949 (Box 25)
  - The Quarterly Review of Biology, 1957 (Box 25)
  - Rahman, 1957 (Box 25)
  - Random House, Inc., 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Rasmussen, A.F., Jr., 1955, 1957 (Box 25)
  - Ray, James D., 1970 (Box 25)
  - Razzell, W.E., 1958, 1961 (Box 25)
  - Rekosh, 1971 (Box 25)
  - Rechsteiner, Martin C., 1990 (Box 25)
  - Reed College, 1960-1961 (Box 25)
  - Reeves, Peter, 1961-1972 (Box 25)
  - Revel, Helen R., 1960, 1971 (Box 25)
  - Reyn, Alice, 1962 (Box 25)
  - Rhoades, Marcus M., 1959 (Box 25)
  - Richards, Christine, 1956-1957 (Box 25)
  - Richards, Fredric M., 1984, 1986 (Box 25)
  - Richards, Jeanne, 1956-1958, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Rickenberg, Howard V., 1959-1963 (Box 25)
  - Riesman, David, 1966 (Box 25)
  - Riker, A.J., 1961 (Box 25)
  - Rita, Geo, 1957, 1962 (Box 25)
  - Rizvi, Saiyid, 1962 (Box 25)
  - Rizzolo, John, 1969 (Box 25)
  - Roberts, Jeffrey W., 1988 (Box 25)
  - Robbins, P.W. (Box 25)
    See Ser.I, Westphal, Otto
  - Robinow, C.F., 1956 (Box 25)
  - Roche Symposium, 1971 (Box 25)
    -See also Ser.III, Ethical Aspects of
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1956-1984 (Box 25)
  - Rockefeller Institute, 1961-1962 (Box 25)
  - The Rockefeller University, 1990-1991 (Box 25)
  - Rockwell, Burton, 1969 (Box 25)
  - Roemer, David K., 1971 (Box 25)
  - Rogers, Adrianne Ellefson, 1976, 1977 (Box 25)
  - Rogers, Paul G., 1973 (Box 25)
  - Rogers, Stanfield, 1960-1967 (Box 25)
  - Roman, Herschel L., 1959 (Box 25)
    See also Ser.I, Annual Review of Genetics
  - Roper, John Alan, 1960 (Box 25)
  - Roscoe, D.H., 1990 (Box 25)
  - Rose, S. Meryl, 1959 (Box 25)
  - Rosebury, Theodor, 1960, 1969 (Box 25)
  - Rosenbaum, Manuel, 1958 (Box 25)
  - Rosenberg, Barbara, 1988 (Box 25)
  - Rosenberg, Barnett, 1976 (Box 25)
  - Rosenberg, Ethel and Julius, 1953 (Box 25)
  - Lewis Rosenstiel Award Committee, 1971-1978 (Box 25)
    Halvorson, Harlyn Orin
  - Rosenzweig, Darlene, 1987 (Box 25)
  - Rossi, Piera, 1966, 1977 (Box 25)
  - Roth, Stephen, 1974 (Box 25)
  - Rotman, Boris, 1959-1972 (Box 25)
  - Rotmann, Raquel, 1949 (Box 25)
  - Rubin, Harry, 1957-1961 (Box 25)
  - Ruby, Ron, 1969 (Box 25)
  - Rudner, Rivka, 1960 (Box 25)
  - Rundell, Mary Kathleen, 1976 (Box 25)
  - Rush-Presbyterian-St. Luke's Medical Center, 1987 (Box 25)
  - Rutgers the State University of New Jersey, 1957, 1987 (Box 25)
  - Ryan, Francis J., 1960 (Box 25)
  - Sabet, Sohair Farid, 1971-1984 (Box 25)
  - Sabik, Joseph Frank, 1981-1983, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Sadosky, Cora, 1977 (Box 25)
  - Sager, Ruth, 1972-1975 (Box 25)
  - Sagers, Richard D., 1961 (Box 25)
  - Sagik, Bernard P., 1953-1960 (Box 25)
  - Sakurai, Kunitomo, 1974 (Box 25)
  - Saletan, Eugene, 1981 (Box 25)
    Nichols, Irene
  - Salk, Jonas, 1966, 1972, 1977 (Box 25)
  - The Salk Institute for Biological Studies, 1965-1982; 12 folders (Box 25)
    Crick, Francis H.C.
    See also Series IIa.
    Bacteriophage and viral genetics; Crick, Francis H. C.; Human genetics; Medical research; Molecular genetics; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder #1, 1965-Jun. 1968 (Box 25)
    - Folder #2, Jul.-Dec. 1968 (Box 26)
    - Folder #3, Jan.-Aug. 1969 (Box 26)
    - Folder #4, Sep. 1969-Feb. 1970 (Box 26)
    - Folder #5, Mar.-Dec. 1970 (Box 26)
    - Folder #6, Jan.-Aug. 1971 (Box 26)
    - Folder #7, 8 Sep. 1971 (Box 26)
    - Folder #8, 8 Sep. 1971 (Box 26)
    - Folder #9, Oct. 1971-6 Feb. 1974 (Box 27)
    - Folder #10, 11 Feb.-Dec. 1974 (Box 27)
    - Folder #11, 1975-Apr. 1978 (Box 27)
    - Folder #12, May 1978-1982 (Box 27)
  - The Salk Institute for Biological Studies--Workshop on the Problems of Drugs and Drug Addiction (Box 27)
    - Folder #1, 1968-Mar. 1969 (Box 27)
    - Folder #2, Apr. 1969-Jan. 1970 (Box 27)
    - Folder #3, Feb. 1970-1972 (Box 28)
  - Salser, Winston, 1967 (Box 28)
  - Salton, M.R.J., 1960 (Box 28)
  - Santer, Melvin, 1957 (Box 28)
  - Sanwal, B.D., 1963 (Box 28)
  - Saphra, Ivan, 1955-1957 (Box 28)
  - Sargent, Francis, 1971 (Box 28)
  - Sarkar, S., 1963-1966 (Box 28)
  - Sartre, Jean-Paul, 1965 (Box 28)
  - Sauer, Robert T., 1984 (Box 28)
  - Sauerbier, W., 1961 (Box 28)
  - Saxe, Linda S., 1973 (Box 28)
  - Schaeffer, Pierre, 1957, 1961 (Box 28)
  - Schein, Stan, 1977 (Box 28)
  - Schlesinger, Milton J., 1971 (Box 28)
  - Schlesinger, R. Walter, 1969, 1989 (Box 28)
    McCarthy, Richard D.
  - Schoenhard, Delbert E., 1961 (Box 28)
  - Schorr, Daniel, 1976 (Box 28)
  - Paul D. Schreiber High School, 1961 (Box 28)
  - Schultz, Jack, 1957 (Box 28)
  - Schwarz, Terek F.R., [1968?], 1972 (Box 28)
  - Science, 1961-1989 (Box 28)
  - Science-Values Synthesis Group, 1981 (Box 28)
  - Scientific American, 1963-1980 (Box 28)
  - Scolnick, Edward M., 1984 (Box 28)
  - Scott, June Rothman, 1969 (Box 28)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons Publishers, 1969-1976 (Box 28)
  - Scuola Normale Superiore, 1976-1977 (Box 28)
  - Seaman, Edna, 1957, 1959 (Box 28)
  - Selikoff, Irving J., 1982 (Box 28)
  - Sells, Bruce H., 1963 (Box 28)
  - Selove, Fay A., 1957 (Box 28)
  - Setlow, Richard B., 1981 (Box 28)
  - Sharp, Phillip A., 1982 (Box 28)
  - Shedlowsky, Alex, 1963 (Box 28)
  - Sheek, Martha, 1952-1968 (Box 28)
  - Sherman, J.M., 1954, 1956 (Box 28)
  - Sherratt, David J., 1979-1980, n.d. (Box 28)
  - Shih, Jason C.H., 1974 (Box 28)
  - Shope, Richard E., 1957 (Box 28)
  - Siddiqi, Obaid H., 1960-1962 (Box 28)
    See also Ser.I, International Cell Research Organization
  - Siegel, Albert, 1957 (Box 28)
    See also Ser.I, Black, Lindsay M.
  - Siev, Moshe, 1965 (Box 28)
  - Signer, Ethan R., 1961, 1964, 1973 (Box 28)
  - Silver, Simon, 1985 (Box 28)
    See also Ser.I, Journal of Bacteriology
  - Siminovitch, Louis, 1987 (Box 28)
  - Simon, Eric J., 1969 (Box 28)
  - Sinauer, Andrew D., 1986 (Box 28)
  - Singer, Jonathan, 1987 (Box 28)
  - Singer, Sam, 1980 (Box 28)
  - Sinha, Rajesh, 1981, 1983 (Box 28)
  - Sinsheimer, Robert L., 1956 (Box 28)
  - Sjögren, Hans, 1961-1962 (Box 28)
  - Skaar, P.D., 1956-1958, 1963 (Box 28)
  - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, 1980-1984 (Box 28)
  - Sloan-Kettering Institute for Cancer Research, 1962 (Box 28)
  - Smith, Derek Austin, 1956-1960 (Box 28)
  - Smith, Hamilton O., 1982 (Box 28)
  - Smith, Paul Francis, 1958 (Box 28)
  - Smith, Sylvia M., 1956-1963 (Box 28)
  - Snyder, Roy W., 1960-1961 (Box 28)
  - Sokatch, John R., 1956-1958 (Box 28)
  - Società Italiana di Fisica, 1963 (Box 28)
    Bernardini, G.
  - Society for General Microbiology, 1951-1958 (Box 28)
  - Society for the Study of Development and Growth (Box 28)
  - Society of American Bacteriologists (Box 29)
    - Folder #1, 1947-Apr. 1956 (Box 29)
    - Folder #2, May 1956-1960 (Box 29)
  - Society of Illinois Bacteriologists, Inc., 1956 (Box 29)
  - Sollner, Barbara, 1970 (Box 29)
  - Solow, Robert M., 1970 (Box 29)
  - Sols, Alberto, 1987 (Box 29)
  - Sonenshein, A.L., 1970 (Box 29)
  - Sonneborn, Tracy M., 1958-1978; 7.0 Item(s) (Box 29)
    American Philosophical Society; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; History of biology, especially genetics; Lectures, public speaking; McClintock, Barbara; Preservation of historical materials; Recommendations
  - Southampton Summer Program, 1974 (Box 29)
  - Soviet Academy of Sciences, 1972 (Box 29)
  - Spiegelman, Sol, 1958-1966 (Box 29)
  - Spock, Benjamin, 1966 (Box 29)
  - E.R. Squibb and Sons, 1952 (Box 29)
  - Stahl, Franklin W., 1961-1962 (Box 29)
    Edgar, Robert S.
  - Stanford University, 1982-1984 (Box 29)
  - Stanier, Roger Yate, 1950, 1962, 1975 (Box 29)
  - Stanley, Wendell M., 1949-1969 (Box 29)
  - Starlinger, Peter, 1960-1961 (Box 29)
  - Staub, Anne-Marie, 1961-1962 (Box 29)
  - Stent, Gunther S., 1957-1981, n.d.; 10.0 Item(s) (Box 29)
    See also Ser.I, Levinthal, Cyrus
    Bacteriophage and viral genetics; Educational matters; Ethical issues; Lwoff, Andre; Radiation genetics
  - Stern, Curt, 1959; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 29)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory
  - Stern, Elias L., 1956 (Box 29)
  - Stewart, Walter W., 1986 (Box 29)
    Feder, Ned
  - Stocker, Bruce A.D., 1957-1963, 1986 (Box 29)
  - Stodolsky, Marvin, 1967 (Box 29)
  - Storc, Roger, 1959 (Box 29)
  - Streisinger, George, 1959-1966, n.d. (Box 29)
    Harrar, Georgetta
    Stahl, Frnaklin W.
    -See also Ser.IIa, Boston Area Faculty Group on Public Issues
  - Strominger, Jack L., 1958, 1961 (Box 29)
  - Stroud, Robert F., 1958 (Box 29)
  - Stuckey, William K., 1969-1970 (Box 29)
  - Suit, Joan Lucia, 1970-1989, n.d. (Box 29)
    Bishop, Lauren J.
    Cramer, William A.
  - Sullivan, John H., 1969 (Box 29)
  - Susan, David C., 1990 (Box 29)
  - Sussman, Maurice, 1956-1957 (Box 29)
  - Suzuki, Yasunosuke, 1982 (Box 29)
  - Symonds, Neville, 1957-1963, n.d. (Box 29)
  - Szent-Györgyi, Albert, 1966 (Box 29)
  - Szilard, Trude, 1964 (Box 29)
  - Takano, Toshiya, 1971-1974 (Box 29)
  - Tanami, Yoh, 1957-1962 (Box 29)
  - Taylor, Austin L., 1960-1961 (Box 29)
  - The Technology Review, 1965-1977 (Box 29)
  - Teegarden, Lillan Elizabeth, 1954 (Box 29)
  - Terawaki, Yoshiro, 1967-1968 (Box 29)
  - Tessman, Irwin, 1956-1960 (Box 29)
  - Thomas, R., 1957-1978 (Box 29)
    Errera, M.
  - Tinelli, Regina, 1963 (Box 29)
  - Ting, Robert C., 1956-1961 (Box 29)
  - Tissue Culture Association, 1956 (Box 29)
  - Todd, Charles W., 1962-1963 (Box 29)
  - Toennies, Gerrit, 1962 (Box 29)
  - Tonhazy, Nicholas E., 1956 (Box 29)
  - Townes, Charles H. (Box 29)
    See also Ser.I, Chamberlain, Owen
  - Trager, George W., 1960-1961 (Box 29)
  - Trautner, Thomas, 1957-1960 (Box 29)
  - Treffers, Henry Peter, 1958, 1961 (Box 29)
  - Trinity University, 1987 (Box 29)
  - Tsipis, Judith Ebel, 1974, 1976 (Box 29)
  - Tufts University, 1977-1981 (Box 30)
  - Mark Twain Society, 1976 (Box 30)
  - Tydings, Joseph D., 1967 (Box 30)
  - Tyler, Jocelyn, 1980 (Box 30)
  - Uchida, Takahiro, 1962 (Box 30)
    Westphal, Otto
  - Uetake, Hisao, 1956-1968 (Box 30)
  - Unesco, 1975 (Box 30)
  - Unidentified, 1954-1985, n.d. (Box 30)
  - Union Internationale Contre le Cancer, 1962-1968 (Box 30)
  - Union of Concerned Scientists, 1969, 1977 (Box 30)
  - United Nations University, 1975 (Box 30)
  - United States. Department of State. Passport Division, 1951-1952 (Box 30)
  - United States House of Representatives. Committee on Science and Technology, 1976, 1986 (Box 30)
  - United States House of Representatives. Select Committee on Crime, 1972 (Box 30)
  - United States. President's Science Advisory Committee, 1970 (Box 30)
  - United States Public Health Service, 1956-1957 (Box 30)
  - Université Libre de Bruxelles, 1977 (Box 30)
  - University of California, 1938-1987 (Box 30)
  - University of Chicago, 1957-1967 (Box 30)
    Beadle, George W.
  - University of Colorado, 1960-1961 (Box 30)
  - University of Delaware, 1956-1963 (Box 30)
  - University of Florida, 1961 (Box 30)
  - University of Illinois, 1956-1988 (Box 30)
  - University of Kansas, 1958 (Box 30)
  - University of Massachusetts, 1977 (Box 30)
  - University of Michigan, 1951, 1980 (Box 30)
  - University of Pittsburg, 1956-1980 (Box 30)
  - University of Puerto Rico, 1961-1988 (Box 30)
  - University of Rochester, 1957, 1973 (Box 30)
    -See also Ser.III, Alternative Tasks for Biologists
  - University of Tennessee, 1961-1962 (Box 30)
  - University of Texas, 1981-1982 (Box 30)
  - University of Utah, 1960-1961 (Box 30)
  - University of Wisconsin, 1958-1959, 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - The Upjohn Company, 1957-1958 (Box 30)
  - Utah State University, 1961-1962 (Box 30)
  - Vanderbilt University, 1956-1958 (Box 31)
    Najjar, Victor A.
  - Van Dyke, James, 1959 (Box 31)
  - Van Tassel, Alfred J., 1959 (Box 31)
  - Vechet, B., 1963 (Box 31)
  - Vitale, Mauricio, 1974 (Box 31)
  - Vogt, Marguerite, 1957 (Box 31)
  - Vogt, Peter, 1958-1959 (Box 31)
  - Volpe, John A., 1969 (Box 31)
  - Wald, George, 1965 (Box 31)
  - Wald, Ruth, 1972 (Box 31)
  - War Tax Resistance, 1969 (Box 31)
  - Warner, Jonathan, 1988 (Box 31)
  - Warshaw, Frances, 1977 (Box 31)
  - The Washington Post, 1962-1979 (Box 31)
  - Washington Square Press, 1982 (Box 31)
  - Washington University School of Medicine, 1990 (Box 31)
  - Wasserman, Felix, 1956, 1958 (Box 31)
  - Watanabe, Tsutomu, n.d. (Box 31)
  - Waterson, A.P., 1961 (Box 31)
  - Watson, James D., 1959 (Box 31)
  - Weigle, Jean, 1956-1962 (Box 31)
    See also Ser.I, Meselson, Matthew
  - Weil, Roger, 1963 (Box 31)
  - Weinberg, Roger, 1960 (Box 31)
  - Weiss, Michael J., 1985-1987 (Box 31)
  - Wellesley College, 1961 (Box 31)
  - Wesleyan University, 1981-1983 (Box 31)
    -See also Ser.III, Ethical and Institutional
  - Western Reserve University, 1956 (Box 31)
    Yanofsky, Charles
  - Westphal, Otto, 1961 (Box 31)
    Robbins, P.W.
    -See also Ser.I, Uchido,
  - WGBH Educational Foundation, 1974 (Box 31)
  - Wheaton College, 1961-1962 (Box 31)
  - White, Abraham (Box 31)
    See Ser.I, Albert Einstein College of
  - White, Brian, 1986 (Box 31)
  - White House Conference on Aging, 1960 (Box 31)
  - Wiberg, John, 1971 (Box 31)
  - Wiesel, Elie, 1985 (Box 31)
  - John Wiley and Sons, Inc., 1956-1969 (Box 31)
  - Williams, Carroll, 1973 (Box 31)
  - Windsor, Isobel, 1956 (Box 31)
  - The Wistar Institute, 1974-1975 (Box 31)
  - Witkin, Evelyn M., 1954, n.d. (Box 31)
  - Wolfe, Ralph, 1958, 1960 (Box 31)
  - Wollman, Elie, 1940 (Box 31)
  - Woo, Yiping Joseph, 1987 (Box 31)
  - World Congress on Community Drug Control, Inc., 1974 (Box 31)
  - World Federation of Scientific Workers, 1971 (Box 31)
  - World Law Fund, 1969 (Box 31)
  - Wormuth, Francis D., 1966 (Box 31)
  - Worth Publishers, Inc., 1968-1969, 1990 (Box 31)
  - Wright, Barbara E., 1961 (Box 31)
  - Wright, Sewell, 1959; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 31)
    Bacteriophage and viral genetics
  - Wu, Shang-Ying, 1966 (Box 31)
  - Yale University, 1959-1988 (Box 31)
  - Yamada, Koichi, 1967 (Box 31)
  - Yanagisawa, Keiko, 1961 (Box 31)
  - Yanofsky, Charles, 1961 (Box 31)
    See also Ser.I, Western Reserve
  - Yarmolinsky, Michael, 1960-1963 (Box 31)
  - Yellin, Edward L., 1960 (Box 31)
  - Young, Nancy, 1974 (Box 31)
  - Youngman, Philip, 1978-1979 (Box 31)
  - Zabin, Irving, 1961 (Box 31)
  - Zacharias, Jerrold, 1972 (Box 31)
  - Zahler, Stanley, 1956-1959 (Box 31)
  - Nicola Zanichelli Editore, 1974 (Box 31)
  - Zazzo, R., 1970 (Box 31)
  - Zebrun, Olga, 1957 (Box 31)
  - Zeisler, Erwin P., 1960 (Box 31)
  - Zelle, Max R., 1956 (Box 31)
  - Zero Population Growth, 1970 (Box 31)
  - Zinder, Norton D., 1956, 1965 (Box 31)
  - Zissler, James, 1966 (Box 31)
- Series IIa. Subject files, 1938-1990; 3.75 linear feet
  Newspaper and magazine clippings; reports and meeting minutes (for the American Society for Microbiology and the Salk Institute for Biological Studies, among others); and various versions of Luria's curriculum vitae. The folders are arranged alphabetically by title. Also included is a statement that Luria made about being blacklisted by the National Institutes of Health (filed under "Blacklisting"); articles written by distinguished scholars for a series organized by Luria for The Boston Sunday Globe (filed under the newspaper title); Columbia Queries, a poll taken by Columbia University on the topic of World War II (Luria's answers are included); reviews of Luria's book, A Slot Machine, A Broken Test Tube; and material about the Nobel Prize, the Boston Area Faculty Group on Public Issues (BAFGOPI), Central America, Vietnam, civil defense, nuclear power, and nuclear arms (filed under those titles).
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1966-1973 (Box 32)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1953, 1955 (Box 32)
  - American Cancer Society, Inc. (Box 32)
    - Folder #1, 1961-1984 (Box 32)
    - Folder #2, 1985 (Box 32)
  - American Society for Microbiology (Box 32)
    - Folder #1, 1965-1966 (Box 32)
    - Folder #2, 1967 (Box 32)
    - Folder #3, Jan.-12 Mar. 1968 (Box 32)
    - Folder #4, 15 Mar. 1968-1970 (Box 32)
  - Annual Pathobiology Conference, 1967 (Box 33)
  - Annual Review of Genetics, 1966-1970 (Box 33)
  - Bibliographies, [196-]-[197-] (Box 33)
  - Blacklisting, 1969 (Box 33)
  - Boston Area Faculty Group on Public Issues (Box 33)
    - Folder #1, 1961-1970 (Box 33)
    - Folder #2, 1972-Feb. 1985 (Box 33)
    - Folder #3, Mar. 1985-1986 (Box 33)
    - Folder #4, 1987-1988, n.d. (Box 33)
  - The Boston Sunday Globe Columnists, 1966 (Box 33)
  - Boston University, 1979-1980, n.d. (Box 33)
  - Brussels Universal and International Exhibition (Box 33)
    See Oversized
  - Central America, 1973-1990, n.d. (Box 33)
    -See also Ser.I, Faculty for Human Rights in El Salvador and Central America
  - Chemical, Biological, and Radiological Warfare, 1959-1970, n.d. (Box 34)
  - The Chicago Medical School, 1954 (Box 34)
  - The Jane Coffin Childs Memorial Fund, 1976 (Box 34)
  - Civil Defense, 1961-1962, n.d. (Box 34)
  - Clippings, 1960-1991, n.d. (Box 34)
  - Columbia University, 1942 (Box 34)
  - Comité Européen des Universitaires pour la Défense de la Démocratie en Grèce, 1969 (Box 34)
  - The Committee of Responsibility, Inc., 1966-1968, n.d. (Box 34)
  - Cuba, 1961-1962 (Box 34)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1938-1982, n.d. (Box 34)
  - Equipment, 1965 (Box 34)
    See also Ser.VII, same title
  - European Conference on Molecular Biology, 1967 (Box 34)
  - Federation of American Scientists (Box 34)
    - Folder #1, 1956-Mar. 1971 (Box 34)
    - Folder #2, May 1971, n.d. (Box 34)
  - Fondation Royaumont, 1971-1976, n.d. (Box 34)
  - Governance of Universities. Rights and Responsibilities: A Study in Academic Ethics, 1968 (Box 35)
  - Hunter College, 1985 (Box 35)
  - India (Box 35)
  - International Cell Research Organization (Box 35)
    - Folder #1, 1962-1974 (Box 35)
    - Folder #2, 1975-1981, n.d. (Box 35)
  - International Laboratory of Genetics and Biophysics, 1964-1965 (Box 35)
  - International Phage Symposium, 1952 (Box 35)
  - International Workshop on Cell Surfaces and Malignancy, 11-13 Sep. 1974 (Box 35)
  - Israel, n.d. (Box 35)
  - Italy, 1983 (Box 35)
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1956 (Box 35)
  - Life: The Unfinished Experiment, 1973-1974, n.d. (Box 35)
  - Lucille P. Markey Charitable Trust, 1984 (Box 35)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital, 1972 (Box 36)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1960-1986, n.d. (Box 36)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology. The Equal Opportunity Committee, 1979-1985 (Box 36)
  - Membrane Journal Club, 1971, n.d. (Box 36)
  - Moleculon Biotech, Inc., 1984-1985 (Box 36)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1966, 1972, 1975 (Box 36)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1953 (Box 36)
  - National Commission on Smoking and Public Policy, 1977 (Box 36)
  - National Institutes of Health, 1958, 1964 (Box 36)
  - National Research Council, 1974-1975 (Box 36)
  - National Research Council. Board of Research on the Effects of Radiation, 1982-1984 (Box 37)
  - National Science Foundation, 1967-1974 (Box 37)
  - The Nature of Virus Multiplicaton, n.d. (Box 37)
  - New York Academy of Medicine, n.d. (Box 37)
  - The New York Academy of Sciences, 1957 (Box 37)
  - Nobel Prize (Box 37)
    - Folder #1, 1969 (Box 37)
    - Folder #2, 1969, 1971 (Box 37)
  - November Action Coalition, [196-] (Box 37)
  - Nuclear Arms, 1957-1984, n.d. (Box 37)
  - Nuclear Power, 1979-1982 (Box 37)
  - Oak Ridge National Laboratory, 1958 (Box 37)
  - Persian Gulf War, 1990 (Box 37)
  - The Polytechnic Insitute of Brooklyn, 1953 (Box 37)
  - Rassegna Della Stampa, 1986 (Box 37)
  - The Salk Institute for Biological Studies (Box 37)
    - Folder #1, 1965-1970 (Box 37)
    - Folder #2, Jan.-Jun. 1971 (Box 37)
    - Folder #3, Jun.-Oct. 1971 (Box 37)
    - Folder #4, 1972 (Box 38)
    - Folder #5, 1973-1974 (Box 38)
    - Folder #6, 1975-1981, n.d. (Box 38)
  - The Salk Institute for Biological Studies--Workshop on Problems of Drugs and Drug Addiction (Box 38)
    -See also Oversized
    - Folder #1, 1968-Feb. 1970 (Box 38)
    - Folder #2, Mar. 1970-1971, n.d. (Box 38)
  - Scientists and Engineers for Political Action, [197-] (Box 38)
  - Segregation, 1956 (Box 38)
  - Selective Service, 1967 (Box 38)
  - Sigma Xi, 1943 (Box 38)
  - A Slot Machine, A Broken Test Tube, 1983-1985, n.d. (Box 38)
  - Society for Social Responsibility in Science, 1956-1957 (Box 38)
  - Society of General Physiologists, 1967 (Box 38)
  - Symposia on Quantitative Biology. XXI. Genetic Mechanisms. Structure and Function, 4-12 Jun. 1956 (Box 38)
  - 36 Lectures in Biology, 1975-1976 (Box 38)
  - Unesco, 1974-1976 (Box 38)
  - Union of Concerned Scientists, 1969 (Box 38)
  - United States-Japan Cooperative Science Program Seminar, May-65 (Box 38)
  - University of Illinois, 1953, 1958, n.d. (Box 38)
  - Vietnam (Box 39)
    See also Ser.IIa, Boston Area Faculty
    - Folder #1, 1964-1966 (Box 39)
    - Folder #2, 1967-1972, n.d. (Box 39)
  - A View of Life, 1980-1981 (Box 39)
  - The Viruses, [1957] (Box 39)
  - Viruses as Determinants of Cellular Functions--Symposium, n.d. (Box 39)
  - The Voice of Reason, n.d. (Box 39)
  - Women Strike for Peace, 1970 (Box 39)
- Series IIb. Personal materials, 1923-1991; 0.75 linear feet
  Items of a personal nature, including letters of condolence sent to his wife after Luria's death; letters in Italian from his brother and father in Italy; poems that Luria wrote; financial materials; Luria's naturalization certificate; and World War II letters in Italian from a girlfriend in Italy before he met his wife.
  - Affidavit in Lieu of Passport, 1940 (Box 40)
  - Back Problems, 1983-1984 (Box 40)
  - Birth Certification, 1977 (Box 40)
  - Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique, 1938-1940 (Box 40)
    in French
  - Commissao Portuguesa de Assistencia aos Judeus Refugiados, 1940 (Box 40)
  - Condolence Letters, 1991 (Box 40)
    - Folder 1, 1991 (Box 40)
    - Folder 2, 1991 (Box 40)
    - Folder 3, 1991 (Box 40)
    - Folder 4, 1991 (Box 40)
  - Condominium, 1980-1989 (Box 40)
  - Etchings, [1990] (Box 40)
  - Family History, 1923 (Box 40)
    See also Ser.IIb, Louria, Jean S.
  - Institut du Radium, 1940 (Box 40)
  - Louria, Jean S., 1971 (Box 40)
    See also Ser.IIb, Family History
  - Luria, Daniel, 1983 (Box 40)
  - Luria, David, 1951 (Box 40)
  - Luria, Franco, 1989 (Box 40)
  - Luria, Giuseppe, 1946-1988, n.d. (Box 40)
  - Memorial Service, 1 Apr. 1991 (Box 41)
  - Naturalization Certificate, 1947 (Box 41)
  - Pochettino, Valeria (Box 41)
    - Folder #1, 1934 - 11 Jun. 1936 (Box 41)
    - Folder #2, 19 Jun. 1936 - 2 Feb. 1937 (Box 41)
    - Folder #3, 7 Feb. 1937 - 8 Apr. 1937 (Box 41)
    - Folder #4, 12 Apr. 1937 - 1938 (Box 41)
    - Folder #5, 1939 - 15 Sep. 1940 (Box 41)
    - Folder #6, 2 Oct. 1940 - 1944 (Box 41)
    - Folder #7, n.d. (Box 41)
  - Poems, n.d. (Box 41)
  - Repligen Corporation Stock, 1981-1990 (Box 41)
  - Social Security Card, n.d. (Box 41)
  - Università Degli Studi di Roma, 1936, 1938 (Box 41)
  - Università Degli Studi di Torino, 1935, 1938 (Box 41)
- Series III. Works by Luria, 1938-1997; 2.75 linear feet